

## Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile: (+81) 070-2811-6113 Japanese level: JLPT N2

Email: <a href="mailto:chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com">chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989">https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989</a>

### Personal profile

I enjoy nothing more than a good challenge, and that's why I thoroughly embrace every problem that needs solving, and work hard to achieve the most efficient code. I am a dedicated developer with project experience in javascript, react, expressJS, SASS and postgreSQL. During my free-time I thrive off challenges and continuously work on improving my coding skills, such as through my projects outlined below. When we meet in person, one of the first things you notice apart from my grit determination, is my ability to work well with others and collaborate as a team.

## **Programming projects:**

My projects and source code can be viewed live on my portfolio here:

https://chris-fletcher-portfolio.netlify.app/

### These include:

- A celebrity recognition AI web app (front and back end)
- A Darts tournament bracket creator app
- A Homepage for a nursery in Tokyo
- A Homepage for a real-estate photography company

### **Personal Achievements:**

- Completing my first large programming project consisting of a front-end, back server and database in 2023.
- Passing the JLPT N2 in 2023.
- Completing the udemy course "The complete web-developer in 2023: Zero to mastery" in 2023.
- Creating and running a successful photography business in 2015.
- Launching a variety of personal projects.

## **Skills**

- Project experience in self taught javascript, react framework, expressJS server building and postgreSQL.
- Working knowledge of python 3.
- Efficient at problem solving and trained through leetcode to narrow down the big O.
- Project experience on both the front and back end, as well as with databases.
- Knowledgeable of DSA patterns and their impact on performance.
- Experience using git commands and the git terminal.

#### **Education**

- Higher Education: The University of Hull, BSc Psychology; achieved in June 2010.
- Udemy course: "The complete web-developer in 2023: Zero to mastery" in July 2023.
- FreeCodeCamp course: Responsive Web Design in February 2023.
- Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT): Level 2 in 2023



# Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile: (+81) 070-2811-6113 Japanese level: JLPT N2

Email: <a href="mailto:chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com">chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989">https://github.com/ChrisFletcher1989</a>

### Recent experience

*Mimmy inc (Minami Aoyama, Tokyo).* June 2021-present <u>Position:</u> Guide Manager

<u>Duties Include:</u> The company teaches children about each country of the world in an aspiration to make global living easier for them in later-life. In charge of a team of roughly 20 domestic staff, and 50 workers overseas in various countries, the position was to oversee the service in general to assure it's quality and educational value to the children. Team-work and motivating those around me to succeed was an important element of this job, and I was able to learn a lot of such skills through it.

### Nova (various locations in Tokyo). April 2017-June 2021

Position: English Language Teacher

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of English materials as a 2nd language. I took a lot of pride in providing the best experience possible for the students and making their goals, my goals. I was working with English language students both in person and online, to all ages from kindergarten age all the way through to retirees.

### AEON (Takadanobaba, Tokyo). August 2014-September 2015

Position: English Teacher

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of a variety of English classes as a foreign language. The daily role included group and private adult lessons of all levels as well as all ages of children's classes. Aside from teaching the lessons, I was responsible for routine counselling of students to help them set and keep their goals. I also had targets for extra materials to sell to the students.

### Haart Estate Agents (South West London). October 2013- August 2014

Position: Senior Sales Negotiator

<u>Duties Included:</u> The role was based around negotiating contracts with those who wish to sell their homes, listening to their requirements and tailoring a plan to their needs. I also was responsible for sales.

### Barnard Marcus (Clapham and Battersea, SW London). May 2012- October 2013

Position: Sales Negotiator

<u>Duties Included</u>: My job was to organise viewings and generate home sales. After negotiating a deal I put in the extra mile to guide it through to completion in a timely manner.